Hello, welcome to this episode of German in Hindi.
Today we are going to
learn an internship which is plus
inflated. This is important because with it
you can make some complex sentences.
Now unfortunately, this is a little bit
not ours, but there is
another advantage for us that it is very
similar to English. So, just for this concept, what
we are going to do is we are going to do it by
using its similarity with English.
So let's see, why do you
say it in English? First, if you
understood that in English, then it is
very easy to do it in German. So,
what happens in English, which is presented to his
in English, take place in the, so
look at this sentence, it will become very
clear to you that how much inch it is because we
use it in English in army day today life.
Look, it tried to learn German. I
tried to learn German. Who is
important to learn German? It is important to
learn German. Or there is no time
to love. There is no time to learn German. You will see its
use in such sentences.  If you do it then first you have to
read the husband's name. To learn German,
in this sentence the second part of the sentence has the
subject for home, there is nothing in it, the
first part of vegetable with Yo Yo Honey Singh
and the word should be kept in the infinitive,
what is there in all the three, that to
learn German behaves similarly, that there is no
subject and two wheeler, two wheeler has
kept all of them in its infinitive and first look at the first
lesson, see
what is there in the first sentence of all the three sentences, it tried to learn
German, Kunwar has used it and tried
to explain to learn German, I hope to learn
German, you can do this from some time onwards,
now you can do this, I to learn German will not
work, then some specific words
which he uses in English, you will drink the first part, the
second test was done, see it is
important to learn German, edit used, you
can say it yourself like this, it is it to
learn German, it is good to learn German, it is
always active, inside and the third job is
used the least  I have no time to learn German,
this is not correct, when I have brought it, I have
no intention to learn, when these three basic
types, by which we make sentences with two plus infinitive, are exactly the
same in German, if you understood till here then it is
very simple, when I have
just said the difference, these essays become essays
like mobile, then it will go
in the end, the rest is research and investigation, okay, so these 13
more types, we will
see one by one in German, what is the first type with
specific var, with specific var is tried to learn
German, tried to learn
German, what will be the price, Farukh Khan bought this Peru,
not only in jeweler, went to NET, the
rest is that
this year during Joker, the bride's support system is
not going on, so we are not getting to play cricket, so what if
we
play that pinned, then what will happen, we are here,
hence this trap is to drink cricket,
absolutely simple, just like there were words in English,
similarly there are some duties in German, that
category  You can use it with it. By the way,
I have given a list of some years here, you will
see Jagdishwar Poster Art and Planets Extra in these and Pure Run
Extra David Engine is installed,
you can see the same list, these general words which you
can use in English,
you can use the same words in German as well,
what is the basic idea, just remember one, the
responsibility of this is lemon, which is very simple, the
second part is even simpler than that,
bike, adjective long and put this in front of it,
important to learn German acid, worthy
kids to learn German acid, fatwa, jeweler, good to learn is simple, let's take another
example, then
important to play, cricket, SS Bisht, cricket,
josh, yellow color, very simple, just
part, third party jam, which is used very rarely,
that is, there, one or butter,
use half, OnePlus, unknown, that I am not time,
if you want to say this, yes, sure arrangement,
stomach, medicine, jeweler, temple, just don't have time, to
learn German, this hubbak, heena side,
during jeweler, these were, by the way, you can make  Yes, there are a
few more that I gave you
like the diet havan, now the 58 last havan
means I don't wish to meet him, I don't have any wish to
disturb the house as per your wish, then you can look up this debtor
or there is a temple nearby,
it's good luck smart 52 jeweler, you
can do this also, further these are a few
constructs with which you can use this,
this will happen very rarely, so that and what we have
seen is very simple that there are
two main, juice plus infinity, what can be there in the first part, there are
some classes which are like
in English, like Faisu Khan,
second, what can be said with guava active,
history sheeter, this is to say, and thirdly, there are
some constructs, this is definitely inside,
this bakayan last and the second part
is normal, like in English, this sentence will be
made normally only with lie, that
lie plus infinitive will go at the end,
remember, this tree got uprooted, which layer
is very simple but now just complete  The concept
when love and I will take if there is any Khan or
analogy then there will be no Swapna Dosh and
in the middle of the block there will be a fight and drowning
analogy then Anju definitely knows for
example a
broad time there is no dimension to call the character
no time to call the center that
this yes definitely inside Kedar analogy
simple and stomach acid character analogy
important 19 stitch loot-loot through and
because of Karna how many times will you use it then
okay so right now the car
is important for you I will say just three
sentences if you will remember this then a
simple subscribe you
can try it this is very important how
unfortunately we have done this in English it is very
important do something to do something if you will
think of any Bhavnagar then which thought canter remains the same then
this sentence will come to mind I often
see me and powder
trying to do this so now this is the point
to the so private English sentences
base rule which I teach remember and concept  It
is very simple, I hope
you have understood this connection, we will meet
in the next episode.